Welcome!
欢迎你
In the last lecture, we successfully recreated this animation blueprint for our character.
在上一节课中，我们成功地为我们的角色重新创建了这个动画蓝图。
And now with everything ready, we can finally start to add in some climbing animations.
现在一切准备就绪，我们终于可以开始添加一些攀爬的动画了。
And we'll be getting animations from Miximal.
我们将从Miximal获取动画。
And this is the pipeline that we'll go through later.
这就是我们稍后要经历的管道。
So first, we'll need to download the Miximal converter.
所以首先，我们需要下载Miximal转换器。
Because the default bone hierarchy from the Miximal's character mesh is not compatible
因为Miximal的角色网格中的默认骨骼层次结构与Unreal不兼容。
with Unreal.
与虚幻系统不兼容。
Using the converter here can save us so much time and trouble for retargeting the animation
在这里使用转换器可以为我们重新定位动画节省大量的时间和麻烦。
that we get.
我们得到的动画。
Once we have the converter ready, we'll need to upload the skeleton you provide to Miximal
一旦我们准备好转换器，我们就需要将您提供的骨架上传到Miximal
in order to have a working conversion.
以便进行有效的转换。
After this step, we can start downloading some animation.
这一步之后，我们可以开始下载一些动画。
The animations that we're gonna get first are for the climb locomotion.
我们首先要得到的动画是用于攀爬运动的。
So it's important here that we take the option in place.
所以在这里，我们采取原地不动的选项很重要。
So we'll want to drive the movement of the animation by our code and not by the animation
所以我们要通过我们的代码来驱动动画的运动，而不是通过动画
itself.
本身。
There will be cases that we want the animation to take over and to drive the movement of
在某些情况下，我们想让动画接管并驱动角色的运动。
our character.
我们的角色。
We'll look at how we can handle that later.
我们将在后面研究如何处理这个问题。
Once we've downloaded all the animations we need, we can enter the conversion process.
一旦我们下载了所有我们需要的动画，我们就可以进入转换过程。
Then you'll be importing and adjusting the animations.
然后你就可以导入和调整动画了。
Since we're getting free animations here, pretty much every animation that we get needs
因为我们在这里得到的是免费的动画，所以我们得到的每一个动画几乎都需要
quite some adjusting before it can be used.
都需要进行一些调整才能使用。
Especially when we need to add room motion to the animations that we get.
特别是当我们需要在我们得到的动画中添加房间运动时。
So if you have access to some higher quality paid assets, it's gonna save you a lot of
因此，如果你能得到一些质量较高的付费资产，这将为你节省大量的
time.
时间。
But once you are familiar with this process, you can pretty much use any animation from
但是，一旦你熟悉了这个过程，你几乎可以在你的游戏中使用任何来自
Miximal in your game.
Miximal的任何动画都可以在你的游戏中使用。
Alright let's get started.
好了，让我们开始吧。
So first we'll need to download the Miximal converter.
首先，我们需要下载Miximal转换器。
You can find the link of this website in the resources drop down.
你可以在资源下拉菜单中找到这个网站的链接。
I've already done this so I'm not gonna download it again.
我已经做了这个，所以我不会再下载它了。
So make sure you have the converter ready, then you can go to miximal.com.
所以请确保你准备好转换器，然后你可以去miximal.com。
First thing that you need to do, you need to click this upload character.
你需要做的第一件事是，你需要点击这个上传字符。
And in here, we need to select a character file and drop it in here.
在这里，我们需要选择一个角色文件，然后把它放到这里。
So this is where I placed my Miximal converter.
所以这就是我放置Miximal转换器的地方。
And to select the character mesh, you need to go inside of this mannequins.
为了选择角色网格，你需要进入这个人体模型的内部。
Since we're using Manny the whole time, we need to go into this Manny Unreal Engine 5.
因为我们一直在使用Manny，所以我们需要进入这个Manny Unreal Engine 5。
And I'm gonna use this SKM Manny Simple.
而我要使用这个SKM Manny Simple。
So we can drag it and place it in here.
所以我们可以拖动它并把它放在这里。
Alright once the uploading is completed, this is what you should see.
好了，一旦上传完成，这就是你应该看到的。
Just click next.
只需点击下一步。
And this is what you should see.
这就是你应该看到的。
And we can start downloading animations we need.
我们可以开始下载我们需要的动画。
So first I'm gonna search Climb.
所以我首先要搜索 "攀登"。
And these are all the Climb animations Miximal has.
这些是Miximal所有的攀登动画。
I'm gonna scroll down.
我将向下滚动。
So the first one that I'm gonna get is this climbing up wall.
所以我将得到的第一个动画是这个爬墙。
So click it.
所以点击它。
And you can see this is the animation.
你可以看到这就是动画。
So make sure you take this in place.
所以请确保你把它放在原位。
And click download.
然后点击下载。
One important setting here is for this skin, make sure you select without skin.
这里有一个重要的设置，对于这个皮肤，确保你选择没有皮肤。
Otherwise you won't be able to have a working animation later when you want to import it
否则，当你想把它导入到虚幻中时，你将不能有一个有效的动画。
to Unreal.
到虚幻中。
Alright I'm gonna click download.
好的，我将点击下载。
So this will be the animation for moving our character up.
所以这将是我们的角色向上移动的动画。
And I'm gonna also download this climbing down wall.
我还要下载这个爬下墙的动画。
And also take this in place option.
还有这个就地取材的选项。
And go to download.
然后转到下载。
Every setting here checks out.
这里的每一个设置都会被选中。
And click download.
然后点击下载。
Alright, that's up and down ready.
好了，这就是上下的准备。
And we still need animations for left, right, and idle.
我们仍然需要左、右和空闲的动画。
So I'm gonna change a new word for searching.
所以我要换一个新词来搜索。
So instead of climb I'm gonna type in hang.
所以我要输入hang，而不是climb。
And press enter.
然后按回车键。
And this press hang shimmy.
然后按hang shimmy。
This is what we need.
这就是我们需要的。
So I'm gonna click this one.
所以我将点击这个。
And take this in place.
然后把这个放在原位。
And click download.
并点击下载。
And click this button.
然后点击这个按钮。
So this is for moving character to the left.
所以这是为了把人物移到左边。
And this one.
还有这个。
We can use this to move our character to the right.
我们可以用这个将我们的角色移到右边。
So take this in place.
所以把这个拿在原地。
Download it.
下载它。
Alright that's up, down, left, and right ready.
好了，这就是上、下、左、右的准备。
And there's this hanging idle.
还有这个悬空的空闲。
So this can be our idle animation.
所以这可以作为我们的闲置动画。
So I'm gonna download it.
所以我将下载它。
Alright that's all the animations that we need for locomotion.
好了，这就是我们需要的所有运动的动画。
And I'm also gonna get some transitioning animations.
我还将得到一些过渡动画。
So this one, brace hang drop.
所以这一个，支撑悬垂。
This can be used when we want to exit the climb state.
这可以在我们想退出爬升状态时使用。
Alright I'm gonna click download.
好的，我将点击下载。
And I'm gonna scroll down.
我将向下滚动。
So this idle to brace hang.
所以这个空闲的支架悬挂。
This can be used when we want to enter the climb state.
这可以在我们想进入爬升状态时使用。
So I'm gonna get this one and click download.
所以我将得到这个动画并点击下载。
Alright that's all the animations we need for now.
好了，这就是我们现在需要的所有的动画。
So these are the animations that I got from MixiMail.
所以这些是我从MixiMail得到的动画。
If you'd like to catch up with me, you can pause the video now and download these animations
如果你想跟上我的节奏，你可以暂停视频并下载这些动画
yourself.
你自己。
Welcome back.
欢迎回来。
Hopefully at this point you have all the animations ready and now we can start the
希望在这一点上你已经准备好了所有的动画，现在我们可以开始
conversion process.
转换过程。
So these are the animations that I just downloaded.
所以这些是我刚刚下载的动画。
So first I'm gonna select all of them and Ctrl+C.
所以我首先要选择所有的动画，然后按Ctrl+C。
Then go inside of this MixiMail converter, inside of this incoming FBX.
然后进入MixiMail转换器，在这个传入的FBX里面。
Double click to open it, then Ctrl+V to place this raw animation inside of it.
双击打开它，然后Ctrl+V把这个原始动画放在里面。
Then I'm gonna go back to this MixiMail converter, double click to open it.
然后我再回到MixiMail转换器，双击打开它。
So left click to continue.
所以左键点击继续。
And enter this conversion process.
并进入这个转换过程。
Scroll down.
向下滚动。
So these are all the animations inside of that incoming FBX folder.
所以这些都是进入FBX文件夹的所有动画。
And you can change the suffix here if you like.
如果你喜欢，你可以在这里改变后缀。
So I'm gonna click here to convert the animations.
所以我将点击这里来转换这些动画。
Alright just like that.
好的，就这样。
Now we can open the folder with converting animations and these are the animations that
现在我们可以打开转换动画的文件夹，这些是我们可以导入到虚幻中的动画。
we can import to Unreal.
我们可以导入到虚幻中。
So go back inside of my project, I'm gonna right mouse button click to create a new folder.
所以回到我的项目里面，我将点击鼠标右键来创建一个新的文件夹。
I'm gonna call this one animation and double click to open it, create another folder.
我要把这个叫做动画，然后双击打开它，创建另一个文件夹。
I'm gonna name it raw.
我将把它命名为raw。
So pretty much every animation needs some adjusting.
所以几乎每一个动画都需要进行一些调整。
I'm gonna place all of these raw animations inside of this folder.
我将把所有这些原始动画放在这个文件夹里。
So double click to open it.
所以双击来打开它。
And I'm gonna minimize this window.
我将最小化这个窗口。
Then I'm gonna select all of these converted animations and drag them to this folder.
然后我要选择所有这些转换后的动画，把它们拖到这个文件夹里。
So first thing we'll need to specify is the skeleton in here.
所以我们首先需要指定的是这里的骨架。
So select this dropdown and select this SK_MANECON.
所以选择这个下拉菜单并选择这个SK_MANECON。
And inside of this MixiMail converter, if you keep scrolling down, you can see these
在这个MixiMail转换器中，如果你继续向下滚动，你可以看到这些
are the configurations for importing animations.
是导入动画的配置。
So you can use this as a reference if you need.
所以，如果你需要，你可以把它作为一个参考。
So basically we'll need to click this advanced dropdown and we need to take this use default
因此，基本上我们需要点击这个高级下拉菜单，我们需要把使用默认的
sample rate and untick this do not import curves.
采样率，并取消勾选不导入曲线的选项。
Then we should be good to go.
然后我们就可以开始了。
Alright, I'm gonna click this import all.
好的，我将点击这个导入所有。
And there you go.
然后你就可以了。
We have our animations.
我们有了我们的动画。
So double click to open this one.
所以双击来打开这个。
So this is our transition animation.
所以这是我们的过渡动画。
And this is the animation that we can use to climb to the left.
这是我们可以用来向左爬的动画。
I'm gonna change the name of it.
我将改变它的名字。
So this shimmy_1, I'm gonna change it to climbed left.
所以这个shimmy_1，我要把它改成向左爬行。
And this one, I'm gonna change it to climbed right.
而这个，我要把它改成向右爬。
And we have this climbing down and this climbing up.
我们有这个向下攀登和这个向上攀登。
I'm sure you can notice between these two animations, there's quite some offset.
我相信你可以注意到在这两个动画之间，有一些偏移。
So later we'll need to adjust them before they can be used.
因此，在使用它们之前，我们需要对它们进行调整。
And we'll have this hanging idle and idle to brace the hang.
而我们将有这个悬挂的空闲和空闲来支撑这个悬挂。
Alright, everything is working properly.
好了，一切都工作正常了。
And in the next lecture, we'll look at how we can actually use these animations.
在下一讲中，我们将看看我们如何能够实际使用这些动画。
So these are the things that you need to be careful with when using animations from Mixmo.
因此，这些是你在使用Mixmo的动画时需要注意的事情。
Feel free to refer back to the video if you need help.
如果你需要帮助，可以随时回看视频。
And I'll see you in the next lecture.
我们在下一个讲座中再见。
[music]
[音乐]